what
e
[Music]
want want
you
e
[Music]
put
for
e
good
[Music]
afternoon
fore
[Music]
speee
for
foreign spee
[Music]
speech
[Applause]
[Music]
bring
[Applause]
uh Sunil good afternoon
good afternoon
dry are you going to try to
share yes one
moment
unmute
you can start Sunil if you
want okay uh good afternoon everyone uh
this is Sunil pal uh your host for this
uh training
session uh as we all aware this that uh
the session will be on barti EXA
guaranteed income plan that is shining
star the plan is
basically given uh keeping the child in
mind and this is considered one of the
best child plans uh
in the guaranteed segment because it has
a flexibility of getting the maturity
amount as a lumsum or in a fiveyear
installments so again the flexibility
lies with
uh the proposer how he want to receive
the money in
future this is purely uh built keeping
in mind uh the higher studies or uh
about the marriage or some lumpsum
amount which may be required by a child
at an age of from 18 years it and it
goes up till uh 29
years so uh shall I start Dr
Ashley yeah you can start you can
start I request everyone to keep their
microphone on the mute so that
disturbance is not
there yeah I I'll manage that I
I'll so uh this is basically
uh non-link non participating uh
non-link uh one moment
okay non-link and nonp participate
participating what does that mean uh it
means that non-link means that insurance
plan or the money obtained uh from the
premium of that plan is not invested any
unit link plan like the the amount is
not
invested in the share market or the
returns are not based on the market
returns and nonparticipating is uh
basically these are guaranteed plans
where what amount what maturity amount a
person will be receiving is
mentioned at the Inception of the policy
only non-participating means that the
fund value or the maturity amount is not
dependent on the company's performance
whatever the performance is whatever is
written in the bond that amount will be
given so again that is not
participating that plan is not
participating in the performance of the
company non-link means it is not linked
to the returns associated with the
market so non-link nonparticipating
generally these plans are called
guaranteed plans in simple
terms
so uh what are the
benefits there is slight change so I'll
convey that the plan is available
from 8 years till 12 years and the
maturity period will be 5 years after
that so if we are paying premium for 10
years the maturity date will be 5 years
after 10 years that is at the end of
15th year at the end of the 15th year
we'll have the option whether we want
the amount as a lsum or as a installment
yearly installments so as a lum if we
need the money uh whole of the money at
one given point of time so that uh we
can decide what has to be done with the
money and generally yearly payouts are
consed where let's suppose the child is
going for a higher study so they they
have to pay some Annual fees and charges
so people ought for annual payout
keeping the higher studies of their
child in
mind so for 10e premium payment term the
policy maturity period will be 5 years
after 10 years so that is 15
years once we'll uh calculate the
premium then we'll come to
know maturity benefits are the
guaranteed
benefits uh it will be written on the
bond paper at what amount uh a person
will be getting at the end of 15 16 17
18 19 20th year depending upon the
premium payment
term uh the beauty of this plan is
that if a death happen happens during
the policy
period the death benefit is paid to the
nominee plus
further premiums are waved off so
further premiums are not to be paid and
the maturity uh period with the maturity
amount the person will also receive the
maturity amount so it it it's a
three-way benefit if death happens
during the policy period death benefit
is the first benefit
waiver of premium is there so no need to
pay further uh premium so that is the
second